<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BDI Code Club</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BDI Code Club</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Version Control with Git, GitHub, and RStudio</title>
      <link>/post/version-control-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/version-control-git/</guid>
      <description>Some Background Science is collaborative. Even a &amp;ldquo;solo&amp;rdquo; projects should be reproducible, meaning we should be thinking about how other researchers can benefit from our work. And we will always have at least one collaborator - our future selves. Each of us has at some point struggled to pick up a project after weeks or month (or even years) of inactivity.
Science is collaborative, and collaboration is hard. Often we aren&amp;rsquo;t trained to collaborate effectively and may be unaware of tools and practices to improve our collaborations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing the maximum computation power of your computer on R</title>
      <link>/post/utilizing-the-maximum-computation-power-of-your-computer-on-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/utilizing-the-maximum-computation-power-of-your-computer-on-r/</guid>
      <description>NotePlease open your R-Studio as an administrator.
OverviewIn this tutorial, we introduce a package to use multiple cores of your system.
After this tutorial you will be able to:
Train a neural network model without using multicoresTrain a neural network model without using multicoresCompare resultsUsing R MarkdownThe tutorial that follows was created using R Markdown. As an exercise in using R Markdown, here, we ask you to save your work in an R Markdown file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDI Code Clinic</title>
      <link>/page/about-full/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about-full/</guid>
      <description>The Big Data Institute (BDI) is an interdisciplinary research institute that focuses on the analysis of large, complex, heterogeneous data sets for research into the causes and consequences, prevention and treatment of disease.Our coding club’s ambition is to create a fun and supportive environment where we develop programming and statistics skills together, across programming languages.We have a many experts in working with Python, R, C++ and many more languages with vast knowledge of cloud computing and HPC and we want to replace statistics anxiety and code fear with inspiration and motivation to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BDI Code Club</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Some info here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>